<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 Jobin Rezai -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.lvnauth.LVNAuth</id>
  
  <name>LVNAuth</name>
  <summary>Create and play visual novels</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <developer id="tld.vendor">
    <name>Jobin Rezai</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      LVNAuth lets you create and play visual novels.
    </p>
    <p>
      Manage your visual novel, from beginning to end, using LVNAuth&apos;s GUI editor. A command system: You can start or stop actions in your visual novel by using some simple commands. A built-in Wizard window will guide you with using commands so you don&apos;t have to memorize the commands. No programming experience required. LVNAuth is made for story writers.
    </p>
    <p>
      Chapters and Scenes: You can have multiple scenes within a chapter. 
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for backgrounds, characters, including the ability to change a character&apos;s image to show a different facial expression, and object images. Images in .png format are recommended.
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for Font Sprite Sheets and Font Kerning. There is also a built-in bitmap font tracing tool to convert variable width font sprite sheets to a fixed width.
    </p>
    <p>
      Compile your story into a .tar.gz or .zip, ready to share with others.
    </p>
  </description>

  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Development</category>
  </categories>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.lvnauth.LVNAuth.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#b3afff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#5c3f5b</color>
  </branding>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <url type="homepage">https://lvnauth.org/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://lvnauth.org/pages/donate.html</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/jrezai/lvnauth/</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_vn_1.png</image>
      <caption>A visual novel made with LVNAuth.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_editor_1.png</image>
      <caption>Writing a script with LVNAuth's built-in editor.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_editor_2.png</image>
      <caption>The wizard window lists all the commands that LVNAuth can use in a visual novel.</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.5" date="2026-06-06">
    <url type="details">https://lvnauth.org/blog/lvnauth-1.5-released.html</url>
<description>
        <p>Improved the font Trace Tool in multiple ways:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added scrollbars.</li>
          <li>Added a new guide line feature to make tracing fonts easier. The guide line is a horizontal line that shows on the generated preview image. The purpose is to assist with making fine-adjustments to the alignment of traced letters. This helps to ensure all characters sit perfectly on the same baseline.</li>
          <li>The generated preview image is no longer in a separate tab; it is shown below a vertical separator, making it quick and easy to see the preview image as tracing happens in real-time.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>The editor now remembers the scrollbar and cursor positions when switching between scripts. When navigating back to a chapter or scene, you will be returned to exactly where you left off.</p>
        <p>Note: These positions are saved for the duration of your session and will reset when the project is closed and reopened.</p>
        <p>Added an option to start visual novels full screen. This option is found in the Story Details window. Full screen can be toggled by pressing F11 or by pressing Alt+Enter. When in full screen, pressing ESC will go to window-mode. Also, the visual novel window is now resizable.</p>
        <p>Pressing the spacebar will now advance the story, similar to a mouse click.</p>
        <p>Bug Fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed bug with the Wizard window not working with the call&gt; command. Before, when the 'OK' button was clicked for the &lt;call&gt; command, an error occurred.</li>
          <li>Fixed bug with &lt;load_&gt; commands not being analyzed when they were in a reusable script, being called via the &lt;call&gt; command in a scene script. Prior to this fix, only chapter scripts were able to run reusable scripts containing &lt;load_&gt; commands and have the sprites be actually loaded. Now with this fix, &lt;call&gt; commands can be used in scene scripts to run reusable scripts containing &lt;load_&gt; commands and the &lt;load_&gt; commands will get analyzed properly.</li>
          <li>Fixed bug with the &lt;call&gt; command causing an error when more than one optional argument was supplied. For example: &lt;call: test, name=Rave, position=4&gt; used to cause an error, due to having 2 optional arguments, but &lt;call: test, name=Rave&gt; worked, because it had 1 optional argument.</li>
          <li>Fixed bug with the &lt;wait_for_animation&gt; command not working when waiting for "all" (simultaneous) animation types.</li>
          <li>Fixed bug with the &lt;background_hide&gt; command not working.</li>
          <li>Fixed bug with the audio cutting off abruptly sometimes while playing music.</li>
          <li>Fixed bug where the Story Details description field was read-only, which was preventing the description from being edited.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
     </release>
   </releases>
</component>