<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 Jobin Rezai -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.lvnauth.LVNAuth</id>
  
  <name>LVNAuth</name>
  <summary>Create and play visual novels</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <developer id="tld.vendor">
    <name>Jobin Rezai</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      LVNAuth lets you create and play visual novels.
    </p>
    <p>
      Manage your visual novel, from beginning to end, using LVNAuth&apos;s GUI editor. A command system: You can start or stop actions in your visual novel by using some simple commands. A built-in Wizard window will guide you with using commands so you don&apos;t have to memorize the commands. No programming experience required. LVNAuth is made for story writers.
    </p>
    <p>
      Chapters and Scenes: You can have multiple scenes within a chapter. 
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for backgrounds, characters, including the ability to change a character&apos;s image to show a different facial expression, and object images. Images in .png format are recommended.
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for Font Sprite Sheets and Font Kerning. There is also a built-in bitmap font tracing tool to convert variable width font sprite sheets to a fixed width.
    </p>
    <p>
      Compile your story into a .tar.gz or .zip, ready to share with others.
    </p>
  </description>

  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Development</category>
  </categories>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.lvnauth.LVNAuth.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#b3afff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#5c3f5b</color>
  </branding>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <url type="homepage">https://lvnauth.org/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://lvnauth.org/pages/donate.html</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/jrezai/lvnauth/</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_vn_1.png</image>
      <caption>A visual novel made with LVNAuth.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_editor_1.png</image>
      <caption>Writing a script with LVNAuth's built-in editor.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_editor_2.png</image>
      <caption>The wizard window lists all the commands that LVNAuth can use in a visual novel.</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

<releases>
    <release version="1.51" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>Improved command-line options for running the player binary executable. You can now use the following switches:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Use <code>--file</code> to specify an .lvna file to execute.</li>
          <li>Use the additional optional switch <code>--show-launch</code> to show the startup window, allowing players to manually choose which chapter or scene to play. Omitting this switch will automatically play the startup scene.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added a new <code>&lt;camera_reset&gt;</code> command to reset the camera zoom and camera position back to their defaults.</p>
        <p>Optimized tint animation behavior: Setting a tint animation speed of 100 will now apply the tint instantly. This applies to tinting commands such as <code>&lt;character_start_tinting&gt;</code>. This is useful for carrying tints seamlessly across scenes without causing the character to quickly untint and retint (eliminating the slight visual flicker).</p>
        <p>Bug Fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a bug that sometimes caused character movement animations to stop 1 pixel short of their intended destination.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
     
   </releases>
</component>