<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2025 Jobin Rezai -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.lvnauth.LVNAuth</id>
  
  <name>LVNAuth</name>
  <summary>Create and play visual novels</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPL-3.0+</project_license>

  <developer id="tld.vendor">
    <name>Jobin Rezai</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      LVNAuth is a desktop application that lets you create and view visual novels.
      Manage your visual novel, from beginning to end, using LVNAuth&apos;s GUI editor. A command system: You can start or stop actions in your visual novel by using some simple commands. A built-in Wizard window will guide you with using commands so you don&apos;t have to memorize the commands. No programming experience required. LVNAuth is made for story writers. Chapters and Scenes: You can have multiple scenes within a chapter. Simple Animations: Ability to apply character and object animations, such as fade, movement, rotate, and scale.
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for backgrounds, characters, including the ability to change a character&apos;s image to show a different facial expression, and object images. Images in .png format are recommended.
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for Font Sprite Sheets and Font Kerning. There is also a built-in bitmap font tracing tool to convert variable width font sprite sheets to a fixed width.
    </p>
    <p>
      Compile your story into a single .lvna file, which can be opened using LVNAuth. Your viewers will need LVNAuth to view your visual novel.
    </p>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.lvnauth.LVNAuth.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#b3afff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#5c3f5b</color>
  </branding>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <url type="homepage">https://lvnauth.org/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://lvnauth.org/pages/donate.html</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/jrezai/lvnauth/</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_story_1.png</image>
      <caption>A visual novel made with LVNAuth</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_story_2.png</image>
      <caption>A visual novel made with LVNAuth</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_wizard_1.png</image>
      <caption>The wizard window lists all the commands that LVNAuth can use in a visual novel.</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.0" date="2025-11-01">
    <url type="details">https://lvnauth.org/blog/lvnauth-0.7.html</url>
      <description>
        <p>Release description</p>
          <ul>
            <li>The license for LVNAuth has been changed from GPLv3 to LGPLv3. This change was made to provide greater flexibility for developers and users who wish to bundle LVNAuth with visual novels or integrate it into other software applications, while still keeping the core of LVNAuth libre. Since LVNAuth functions both as a visual novel editor and a player, the LGPLv3 license better suits its dual purpose and encourages broader use and distribution.</li>
            <li>Added the ability to create and play web-connected visual novels. These are visual novels that can fetch and save data from and to a remote web server managed by LVNAuthWeb (a new terminal-based web application used for interacting with visual novels).</li>
            <li>Added new remote commands: `*<remote_get>*`, `*<remote_save>*`, `*<remote_call>*`. These are used for getting a saved value from a remote server, saving data to a remote server, and running a remote script on a web server, respectively. This opens up the possibility to generate LVNAuth scripts on a web server, dynamically. For example, you could have a character tell you the current weather by getting the weather info from a web server, create your own AI character responses and more.</li>
            <li>Added `*<halt_and_pause_main_script>*` and `*<unpause_main_script>*` commands to the Wizard. These two commands were introduced in version 0.6 but were not listed in the Wizard until now.</li>
            <li>Fixed bug: using multiple optional arguments caused the visual novel to crash. This affected commands that accept multiple optional arguments, such as `*<call>*`, `*<after>*`</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
     </release>
   </releases>
</component>