<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2024 Jobin Rezai -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.lvnauth.LVNAuth</id>
  
  <name>LVNAuth</name>
  <summary>Create and play visual novels</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <developer id="tld.vendor">
    <name>Jobin Rezai</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      LVNAuth is a desktop application that lets you create and view visual novels.
      Manage your visual novel, from beginning to end, using LVNAuth&apos;s GUI editor. A command system: You can start or stop actions in your visual novel by using some simple commands. A built-in Wizard window will guide you with using commands so you don&apos;t have to memorize the commands. No programming experience required. LVNAuth is made for story writers. Chapters and Scenes: You can have multiple scenes within a chapter. Simple Animations: Ability to apply character and object animations, such as fade, movement, rotate, and scale.
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for backgrounds, characters, including the ability to change a character&apos;s image to show a different facial expression, and object images. Images in .png format are recommended.
    </p>
    <p>
      Support for Font Sprite Sheets and Font Kerning. There is also a built-in bitmap font tracing tool to convert variable width font sprite sheets to a fixed width.
    </p>
    <p>
      Compile your story into a single .lvna file, which can be opened using LVNAuth. Your viewers will need LVNAuth to view your visual novel.
    </p>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.lvnauth.LVNAuth.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#b3afff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#5c3f5b</color>
  </branding>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <url type="homepage">https://lvnauth.org/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://lvnauth.org/pages/donate.html</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/jrezai/lvnauth/</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_story_1.png</image>
      <caption>A visual novel made with LVNAuth</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_story_2.png</image>
      <caption>A visual novel made with LVNAuth</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://lvnauth.org/images/screenshots/lvnauth_wizard_1.png</image>
      <caption>The wizard window lists all the commands that LVNAuth can use in a visual novel.</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.7" date="2024-11-01">
    <url type="details">https://lvnauth.org/blog/lvnauth-0.7.html</url>
      <description>
        <p>Release description</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Added a feature to edit existing commands by right-clicking and choosing the menu, 'Edit line'. This will allow you to change the values of commands using the Wizard window. Prior to this, the Wizard window was only able to generate new commands; but now the Wizard window can edit commands that are being used in a visual novel.</li>
            <li>Added the ability to play from the Startup scene via the Play button, without the launch window. Before, it would show a Launch window first. Starting the visual novel from the Launch window is still an option, however.</li>
            <li>Added optional arguments support for the call command in the Wizard window.</li>
            <li>Added optional arguments support for the command: 'after'. This allows arguments to be passed to a reusable script.</li>
            <li>Fixed bug with the 'case' command causing an error when no condition name was provided. The condition name is optional unless you want to use 'or_case' later on.</li>
            <li>Fixed bug with the variables editor window not saving numeric values.</li>
            <li>Cleaned up the command helper descriptions that show up near the bottom of the editor window. For example, instead of the description '*Character sprite to load (no extension)*', it now shows '*Character sprite name*'. Also, a few inaccurate parameter descriptions were corrected.</li>
            <li>The visual novel project will now be saved automatically just before being played via the 'Play' button in the editor window. This way, the latest changes will be saved without needing to manually click the 'Save' button every time before playing your visual novel.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
     </release>
   </releases>
</component>